MAX MURPHY, BA

Detroit, MI | 810-820-1908 | murphymax1@gmail.com LinkedIn | Github | Bloq | Portfolio

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full Stack Developer with experience in JavaScript, ReactJS, and Ruby on Rails. Professional experience in audio engineering/production that includes Avid Pro Tools, Adobe Audition, and Logic Pro X. Excited to contribute my success and aptitude in artistic sound engineering to create innovative solutions using new technologies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: Javscript, React, Ruby, HTML, CSS, SQL

Tools: React.is, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, DSA, OOP, Relational Databases, Git, Heroku, Firebase, p5.is

Audio: DAWs - Avid Pro Tools, Adobe Audition, Logic Pro X

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Hopper's Books - Flatiron School Final Project - Github | Demo

Secure Rails/React app for an eCommerce site for a frog-themed bookstore.

- Developed front-end using React.is, and CSS to create a streamlined user experience
- Built PostgreSQL relational database, backend/Rails API structure, and dynamic seeding following the MVC framework
- Dynamically rendered search page book data based on Google Books API endpoints
- Utilized a many-to-many table association for individual user wishlist and purchase data

Spats - Spotify Stats - Flatiron School Project Github | Demo

React/Rails app for viewing your top tracks and artists on Spotify.

- Integrated a React UI with the Spotify for Developer's Web API to provide users with on-demand listening data.
- Compiled listening stats into seed data to create novel music recommendations based on user statistics.

Extraterrestrial Twinning (E.T.T.) - Flatiron School Project - Github | Live

React app featuring a space-themed card-matching game.

- Developed front-end using React is, and CSS to create a streamlined user experience
- Built out card randomization with matching functionality, as well as corresponding score and timer components

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Impact 89fm East Lansing, MI **Production Director** 09/2018 - 05/2020

- Utilized DAWs (Digital Audio Workstations) to produce weekly promos, PSAs, and other on-air content
- Directed weekly volunteer meetings (of 12-15 participants) to facilitate understanding of audio production
- Assisted in the production and broadcast of weekly live in-studio music performances
- Established a welcoming atmosphere for music lovers as a daytime radio DJ

Mac's Bar Lansing, MI **Sound Technician** 08/2019 - 03/2020

- Managed and implemented audio recording and mixing equipment to run live sound for a 112 capacity venue
- Set stage and sound in time-sensitive settings with efficiency to ensure timeliness of event

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Remote 03/2022 - 07/2022

Certification - Software Engineering - Full Stack Web Development

Michigan State University

East Lansing, MI

Bachelor of Art (BA) - Media and Information | Minor: Leadership of Organizations

05/2020